時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
노부나가의 본거지를 발견한 무사시 일행은 이 방법 저 방법을 쓴 끝에, 어떻게든 바벨 13에 잠입했다.
After discovering the base of Nobunaga, after all the possible ways, Musashi and others managed to invade into Babel 13.
노부나가를 쓰러트리기까지 한 보 직전까지 간 무사시 일행이지만, 한조의 함정에 빠져, 그 목숨은 풍전등화.
Right before taking Nobunaga down, they fell into Hanzō's trap, and their lives are at stake.
과연 무사시 일행의 운명은 어찌?
What will happen to them?
바벨 13을
부수어라 이오
Destroy
Babel 13
괜찮냐, 무사시!
Are you okay, Musashi?
아, 까딱하면 익사체가 될 뻔했소!
I almost ended up drowning-dasu!
꼴 좋다. 계속 날 괴롭혀 온 대가다!
What a sight. That's what you get for trying to get in my way!
네이놈! 네가 원하는 대로는 안 된다!
You bastard! Whatever you want won't happen!
소용 없다, 소용 없어!
No use, no use!
젠장! 이런 곳에서 죽고 싶지 않아!
Damn! I don't want to die here!
나, 오츠루가 만든 단고 더 많이 먹기 전까지는 못 죽소!
I can't die until I eat more of Otsuru's dangos-dasu!
살려줘도 좋다.
You can release them.
살려 주는 것이오? 이야, 노부나가 씨 좋은 사람이오!
Are you saving us-dasu? Mr. Nobunaga, you're a good guy-dasu!
그 대신, 센히메가 어디 있는지 알려주지 않겠나.
In exchange for that, tell me where Senhime is.
뭣이오!?
What-dasu!?
센히메 님을 어쩔 생각이냐!
What are you going to do with Senhime!?
뻔한 걸. 인질로 잡아 이에야스에게 제너럴의 자리를 넘기도록 하려는 것이다.
It's obvious. I'll take her as a hostage and make him pass over the seat of General.
나쁜 놈이오!
You're cruel-dasu!
흥. 이래 보여도 난 괜히 피를 흘리게 하는 건 싫다.
Hmph. No matter what you think, I do not like to see unnecessary blood.
그, 그렇습니다!
Y- you're right!
그렇습니다.
That's right.
만약 우리가 에도토피아에 총공격을 하면 어떻게 될 것 같나.
What do you think about that what'll happen if we do an all-out attack to Edotopia?
에도토피아는 불바다가 되고, 죄 없는 많은 사람들의 목숨이 없어지게 되겠지.
Edotopia will become a sea of fire, and numerous lives of people without any wrongdoing will be lost.
센히메만 인질로 잡으면, 누구도 고통스럽지 않게 내게 천하가 넘어올 것이다.
By taking Senhime as a hostage, nobody will suffer, and the world will fall under my hands.
이해했소. 분명 그렇소.
I see, that makes sense-dasu.
멍청아! 적의 작전에 감탄하는 놈이 어디 있냐!
You idiot! Who in the world gets struck with admiration for enemy's strategy!?
너희 부탁이라면 죽어도 거절한다!
We will refuse your favor, no matter what it is, even if I have to die!
소인도다!
Me too!
나도야!
그럼 어쩔 수 없지. 도쿠간류!
If you say so... Dokuganryu!
예.
Yessir.
병사를 데리고 이 주변 섬을 샅샅이 뒤져서 센히메를 잡아 와라.
Take some soldiers, search the neighboring islands, and capture Senhime.
알겠습니다.
Understood.
잠깐. 반항한다면 죽여도 좋다.
Wait. If they resists, you may kill them.
그, 그러나 그리하면 인질의 의미가...
B- but, what's the point of taking hostage then?
무슨, 살아 있는지 죽어 있는지 따위는 아무래도 상관없다. 센히메의 몸만 있다면 이에야스 따위는 어떻게든 협박할 수 있다.
Know that whether Senhime is alive does not matter. With Senhime's body, blackmailing Ieyasu is easily done.
이놈들! 오센짱한테 손가락 하나라도 대면 내가 용서 안 하오!
You bastards! If you even touch Senhime, then I won't forgive you-dasu!
무사시하고 얘들 다 늦네...
They are being late...
이렇게 지루할 줄 알았으면 나도 갈걸.
Maybe I should went with them, since it's so boring here.
그런 말 하면 안 돼요! 무사시 씨하고 다들 지금 목숨을 걸고 싸우고 있어요!
You can't say that! Mr. Musashi and everyone are fighting to their best!
신님!
Lord!
오츠루...
Otsuru...
뭐, 그 놈들이니까 그렇게 간단히 잡힐 리는 없겠지.
Well, you know who they are. They won't get caught so easily.
아, 그보다도, 자, 됐어! 군고구마!
More importantly, here are your roasted sweet potatoes!
역시 겐나이 씨! 대천재!
Mr. Gennai is the best! Super genius!
왜 그러냐, 오츠루. 안 먹어?
What's wrong, Otsuru? Aren't you eating one?
-그래, 고민이 있어도 어쩔 수 없어.
-그래, 그래!
-Even you feel uneasy, it's not like we can help.
-Yeah, right!
신이여, 무사시 씨가 싸우고 있을 동안 고구마의 유혹에 넘어가 버린 저를 용서해 주세요.
Dear God, please forgive me for falling over to the temptation of sweet potatoes while Mr. Musashi is fighting.
꼭 무사시 씨하고 다들 무사히 돌아올 수 있도록.
Please let Mr. Musashi and everyone come back safely.
이제 신에게 빌어도 무사시 놈들은 안 돌아온다!
Pray all you want, but Musashi and others won't come back anymore!
뭐, 뭐야, 너희들. 여자얘가 있는 방에 노크도 안 하고 들어오다니 실례잖아!
W- what are you guys? Entering a girl's room without knocking is rude!
무사시 씨가 돌아오지 못한다니 무슨 의미에요!?
What do you mean by that Mr. Musashi and others won't be able to come back!?
흥, 지금쯤이면 물고문으로 죽었겠지.
Hmph. They should've died by now by water torture.
오, 오츠루!
O- Otsuru!
자, 센히메 님, 순순히 우릴 따라오시지.
Now, Senhime, you should follow us without resisting.
싫어!
No way!
그럼 어쩔 수 없지.
Well then.
죽이더라도 데리고 갈 뿐이다.
We only have to take you, even if we have to kill you.
뭐야, 뭐야! 여럿이 달라붙어 여자얘들을 괴롭히다니 최악이야!
What is this!? Ganging up on girls is the worst!
여기에 들어와라!
Come into here!
흥! 자, 물러설 곳도 없지?
Hmph! You have nowhere to go.
그래?
I wonder.
해냈어! 대단해, 겐나이 씨!
You did it! You're awesome, Mr. Gennai!
천재에게 불가능 따위는 없다!
Nothing is impossible to a genius!
쫒아라!
Get them!
겐나이 씨! 금방 부서질 거야!
Mr. Gennai! This won't hold for long!
(조금 저림, 저림, 완전 저림, 막 저림, 탐)
(a little bit numb, numb, totally numb, extremely numb, burn)
괜찮다. 혼내 줄 테니까.
It'll be alright. I'll teach them a lesson.
으쌰! 으쌰! 으쌰! 으쌰!
Push! Push! Push! Push!
했나?
Did it work?
왜 그러냐!
What's wrong!?
뭐야!?
What's going on!?
뭐야, 이건!?
What's this!?
보았냐? 이거야말로 겐나이 씨의 발명품 중에서 걸작 중의 걸작! 전기다.
Did you see? This is the masterpiece of masterpiece among the inventions of me, Mr. Gennai! It's electricity!
할배가 묘한 걸 꺼내고!
A geezer with a weird thing, eh?
뭘 하고 있냐! 덤벼라!
What are you doing? Get him!
안 돼!
No!
-겐나이 씨, 대단해!
-쓸데없이 나이 먹은 게 아니었어!
-Mr. Gennai is awesome!
-He's worth being that old!
맡겨 둬라!
Leave it to me!
너희들같은 카라쿠리 무예가는 전기에는 약하지.
Karakuri martial artists like you are weak to electricity.
제기랄!
Damn!
자, 자, 자, 자, 너희가 안 온다면 내가 간다.
Well, well, if you aren't going to come, then let me make a move first.
이랴! 이랴!
Take this! Take this!
가, 가, 가, 가! 겐나이 씨!
Go, go, go, go, Mr. Gennai!
어, 어라? 넌 마비 안 되냐?
H- huh? Don't you become numb?
겐나이 씨, 이거, 이거!
Mr. Gennai! This! This!
어!?
What!?
이야, 이건 절호의 죽을 날이구나.
Oh, today must be my last day.
웃기지 마라, 할배!
Don't fool around, geezer!
아, 기껏 잘 될 참이었는데!
We were so close!
도망쳐라!
Run!
네!
Yes!
젠장!
Damn!
잡아라!
Get them!
뭐, 뭐야!?
W- what's this!?
어서 타라!
Get on!
네!
Yeah!
에잇, 멈춰라!
Stop right there!
좋아, 출발!
Great! Take off!
더는 어디 못 갈 테니까. 해치워라!
You won't be going anywhere now. Finish them!
누, 누구냐!
W- who was that!?
전 에도 808정을 지키는 제니가탄이 상대다!
The protector of whole 808 villages of Edo, Zenigatan, will face you!
두목!
Boss!
벤케이 납셨다!
Benkei's here!
가련한 소녀나 무력한 노인을 상대하다니, 카라쿠리 무예가의 행위로써, 검이 용서하더라도 이 내가 용서할 수 없습니다!
Your sword may forgive fighting feeble girls or powerless old men, but I won't forgive that action of a Karakuri martial artist!
우시와카! 멋져!
Ushiwaka! You look cool!
겐나이 씨, 괜찮아요?
Mr. Gennai, are you okay?
아이고, 허리를 부딪혔다.
My back hurts...
먹어라!
Take this!
제기랄!
Damn!
퇴각!
Retreat!
살았어, 우시와카!
You guys saved us, Ushiwaka!
센히메 님도 무사해서 다행입니다.
It's a relief that you're safe, Senhime.
그래도, 왜 다들 여기에 온 거야?
But, how did you make it here?
주베 님께서 적의 아지트가 가까이 있다는 알림을 받아, 저것에 타서 달려왔습니다.
We were notified that the hideout of the enemies are nearby by Mr. Jūbee, and so we hurried our way to here.
그래! 저기에 타서 무사시하고 다들 구하러 가자!
Yeah! Let's ride on that and go save Musashi and others!
좋다! 일분 일초가 중하니!
Great! Even one second is important now!
좋아!
Right!
무사시 씨, 살아 있어!
Mr. Musashi, be alive!
으악! 활약은 전혀 못 하고 죽는 건 싫소!
Wah! I don't want to die, before doing anything big at all-dasu!
무사시! 큰 소리 내면서 공기 잔뜩 들이쉬지 마!
Musashi! Don't be loud and use up all the air by ylurself!
너 때문에 더 빨리 죽게 됐잖아!
We're going to die earlier than them because of you!
-왜이오!
-저걸 봐 봐라!
-Why-dasu!?
-Take a look at that!
꼴 좋다. 너희에게 어울리는 비참한 끝이지.
What a sight. That miserable way of dying really suits you guys.
젠장! 극악인! 인비인! 한이 맺힐 것이오!
Damn! Scoundrel! Brute! I'll curse you-dasu!
유쾌하군, 유쾌해!
How pleasant!
뭔 일이냐!
What's going on!?
누군가가 이 바벨 13에 공격해 오고 있습니다!
Something is coming to attack this Babel 13!
뭐야!?
What!?
무슨. 메가톤성이 아니냐.
Isn't that Megaton Castle?
어떻게 된 거냐!
What's going on!?
잘 모르겠습니다! 처박으러 오고 있습니다!
I don't know, but it's coming to crash!
아, 아니잖아! 저건 메가톤성이 아니야!
I- it isn't! That isn't Megaton Castle!
무사시 일행은 구출받을 것인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Will Musashi and others be rescued? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
저, 저건!
N- no way!
젠장, 누구냐!
Damn, who is it!?
무사시 님, 무사했군요.
Mr. Musashi, you were safe.
어서 꺼내 주시오.
Get me out of here-dasu.
지금 구해 드리겠습니다.
I'll rescue you right away.
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
오츠루, 와 주었소! 모두!
Otsuru, you're here-dasu! Everyone too!
정말 감사합니다. 덕분에 살았습니다.
Thank you so much. You saved us.
아닙니다. 동료가 위기에 처했을 때에는 구하는 게 당연하지요.
It's nothing. It is obvious to rescue a friend in danger.
서먹한 소리 하지 마셔요.
Don't act as if we're distant!
그렇다!
Yeah!
모였구나. 옛날의 원한은 오늘로 끝장내 주겠다!
So everyone's here. I'll finish all of you up today!
우리 팀워크는 무적이오! 다들 가오!
Our teamwork makes as invincible-dasu! Let's go, everyone-dasu!
이천일류 섬광권!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
잘도 나를 수장시키려 했겠다!
You dared to drown me!
멈춰라!
Stop!
개구리의 원한은 무섭다고!
The grudge of a frog is fearful!
한조! 네 야망은 여기서 끝이다!
Hanzō! Your ambition falls here!
웃기지 마라. 네게 당할 내가 아니다!
Don't be stupid. You won't take me down!
조조 아머!
Sousou Armor!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
초히 아머!
Chohi Armor!
뇌명환!
Raimeimaru!
설마 놈들의 동료가 오리라고는... 면목이 없습니다, 노부나가 님.
I did not expect their comrades to come. I deeply apologize, Lord Nobunaga.
뭐, 됐다. 인질 따위 없어도 곧 지팡구국은 내 것!
Well, good enough. Even without a hostage, Jipangu State is as good as mine!
무슨 일이냐!
What's going on!?
보고드립니다! 무사시 놈들이 수조에서 도망쳐 날뛰고 있습니다!
Report! Musashi and others came out from the water tanks and they're raging!
뭐야!?
What!?
신났구만. 내가 베어 넘겨뜨려 주겠다!
They must be so excited. Let me chop them down!
잠시 기다려 주십시오, 노부나가 님.
Please wait, Lord Nobunaga.
말참견하지 마라!
Do not butt in!
아니, 저런 놈들에게 노부나가 님께서 직접 칼날을 드실 필요는 없습니다.
We are saying that you do not need to use your sword by your own.
그렇습니다! 저런 놈들은 저와 켄신만으로 충분합니다!
That's right! Those bunch are enough only by Kenshin and me!
그렇다면 너희들에게 맡기겠다! 잘 처리하고 와라!
Then, I'm leaving this to you. Do not come back until you finish them!
예!
Yessir!
무사시 님. 여기는 저희에게 맡기시고 노부나가를 쓰러트리러 가 주세요!
Mr. Nobunaga. Leave this to us, and please go take down Nobunaga!
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
-코지로!
-좋다!
-Kojirō!
-Right!
어딜 가나.
Where do you think you're going?
노부나가 님에게는 못 간다!
You will not see Lord Nobunaga!
에잇, 방해되오!
You're getting in my way-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
먹어라!
Take this!
이대로라면 당하고 마오!
I'll be done for at this rate-dasu!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
겐토쿠 아머!
Gentoku Armor!
젠장!
Damn!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
칸우 아머!
Kanu Armor!
괜찮냐!
Are you alright?
역시 내겐 네 힘이 필요한 것 같구나.
It seems that I do need your powers.
다가와라! 나도 마찬가지다!
Come closer! Same for me too!
-가자!
-좋아!
-Let's do this!
-Right!
천지합체! 신겐신!
Sky Ground Fusion! Shingenshin!
자, 놀이는 여기까지다!
Playtime ends now!
무사시! 잠깐 여기도 부탁한다!
Musashi! Take care of this for a moment!
어, 코지로! 오줌이오?
Huh, Kojirō? Going to pee-dasu!?
어서 갔다오시오!
Come back as soon as possible-dasu!
봉황환! 불사조의 춤!
Hououmaru! Dance of Phoenix!
해냈소!
We did it-dasu!
감히 했겠다, 꼬맹이들아!
How dare you do that, brats!?
기껏 편하게 저 세상에 보내주려 했더니...
I was thinking about sending you to the other world in peace, but...
순순히 죽어라!
Do a favor and die!
무사시 님!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
감히 오츠루를! 나 화났소!
How dare you do that to Otsuru!? I'm mad-dasu!
이천일류 쌍룡검!
Niten'ichiryū: Double Dragon Sword!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
왜 그러냐, 무사시!
What's wrong, Musashi?
나, 방금 그것으로 힘을 다 써 버렸소. 배가 고프오...
I just used up all my power by that-dasu. I'm hungry-dasu...
자, 무사시 씨! 단고!
Here, Mr. Musashi! Your dangos!
우오아, 오츠루, 고맙소!
Otsuru, thank you-dasu!
신겐신!
Shingenshin!
제기랄!
Damn!
멈춰라!
Stop!
주베 씨!
Mr. Jūbee!
쫓읍시다!
Let's chase them!
좋아!
Right!
노부나가 님!
Mr. Nobunaga!
왜 그러냐! 놈들을 처리했나!
What's wrong!? Did you get them?
아니, 신겐신이 당했습니다!
No, Shingenshin is down!
뭣이!? 신겐신이!?
What!? Shingenshin!?
다음은 네 차례이오!
It's your turn now-dasu!
자, 각오해라!
Now, prepare yourselves!
국왕 전하에게서 빼앗아 간 삼종의 신기를 돌려줘!
Give us back the Three Sacred Treasures that you stole from the Highness!
뭐라? 건방진 계집애가!
What!? You impudent girl!
멈춰라!
Stop!
삼종의 신기인가. 흥. 신겐신을 쓰러트린 너희 힘은 대단한 것이군. 내가 졌다.
The Three Sacred Treasures, eh? Hmph. I praise your powers, for being able to take down Shingenshin. I lost.
뭣이오?
What-dasu?
방의 모퉁이를 봐 봐라!
Take a look at the corner of this room!
기쁘다! 드디어 되찾았어!
I'm so happy! I finally got it back!
국왕 전하가 칭찬해 주실까?
Will the Highness praise me?
센히메 님, 고마워요. 결혼해요.
Senhime, thank you. Let's marry.
네, 물론!
Yes, of course!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
어, 코지로, 안 돼, 내게는 국왕 전하가...
No, Kojirō! I have the Highness!
속였겠소!
You fooled us!
안녕이다!
Farewell!
저런. 달아나 버렸군요.
Well. They ran away.
왜 그러냐, 벤케이!
What's wrong, Benkei!?
출입구가 막힌 것 같습니다.
It seems that the exit is blocked.
젠장! 또 갇히고 말았어!
Damn! We're trapped again!
도쿠간류, 바벨 13 자폭 스위치를 눌러라!
Dokuganryu, press the self-destruction switch of Babel 13!
바벨 13을 버릴 생각입니까?
Are you going to abandon Babel 13?
이런 건 더는 필요 없다.
I do not need such thing anymore.
지금부터는 에도 성이 내 성이다!
From now on, Edo Castle is my castle!
에도토피아에 총공격을 해라!
Do a full-out attack to Edotopia!
예!
Yessir!
자폭 스위치 작동합니다.
Self-destruction switch, now turning on.
바벨 13, 폭발까지 앞으로 3분. 어서 피난을 개시해 주십시오.
3 minutes until the explosion of Babel 13. Please evacuate immediately.
결혼하지도 못하고 죽는 건 싫어!
I don't want to die before being able to marry!
나도 오츠루하고 결혼하고 싶었소!
I wanted to marry Otsuru-dasu!
저런, 무사시 씨도 참, 모두 앞에서!
Mr. Musashi, don't say that in front of everyone!
오츠루...
Otsuru...
폭발까지 앞으로 1분.
1 minute until explosion.
네이놈!
You bastard!
폭발까지 앞으로 30초.
30 seconds until explosion.
초읽기 시작합니다.
Beginning countdown.
폭발까지 앞으로 10초.
10 seconds until explosion.
이제 남은 건 이에야스 뿐인가.
Only Ieyasu stands in my way now.
저건 메가톤성. 젠장, 에도토피아로 갈 생각이군.
That is Megaton Castle. Damn, it's heading to Edotopia!
그 말은, 놈들이...
That means, those guys...
당하고 만 건가!
Are they gone!?
저런! 센히메도 오츠루도 앞으로 수영복 차림을 못 보면 난 슬퍼!
No! I will be remaining sad if I won't be able to see Senhime and Otsuru's looks in swimsuits!
겐나이 씨!
Mr. Gennai!
수영복 차림이 뭐?
Swimsuits what?
아니, 난, 다들 무사했구나, 다행이야.
Uh, I mean, you're all safe! What a relief!
그렇소!
You're right-dasu!
절체절명의 위기에 빠졌던 무사시였지만, 우시와카나 벤케이의 뜨거운 우정으로 궁지를 탈출할 수 있었다.
Musashi and others were in dire crisis,
but they managed to escape the danger, thanks to the burning friendship of Ushiwaka and Benkei.
지지 마라, 무사시! 싸워라, 무사시! 뜨거운 우정 파워를 전개해서 노부나가의 야망을 꺾어라!
Do not lose, Musashi! Fight, Musashi! Use all your burning friendship powers to take down Nobunaga's ambitions!
싸우고 맞았어
I fought and I got beaten
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
I can't lose, so take my blow!
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
다음 시간 즐거운
Next is delightful lunchtime
급식일 텐데
But it's not delightful today
선생님의 벼락이
The thunder of my teacher
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
only hit me and nobody else
사정을 말해도
I tried to explain
들어주지 않는 채
But he won't listen
어떻게 해도 역시
Now whatever I do
눈물이 나오고 말아
I end up crying
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
왠지 안타까워
you'll feel downhearted
육도마왕 노부나가는 메가톤성으로 에도토피아를 타버린 불판으로 만들 생각이오.
Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh is trying to make Edotopia into a burnt field-dasu.
그 쯤, 닛코에 숨어 있던 국왕 전하는, 초공전이라고 하는 하늘을 나는 탈것에 타서 에도토피아로.
Meanwhile, the Highness, who was hiding in Nikko, rides a flying machine named Chokuden to fly over to Edotopia.
우리는 필사적인 각오로 메가톤성에 올라타 노부나가의 야망을 저지하기 위해 힘내오!
We get onto Megaton Castle with a desperate resolution, and do our best to stop Nobunaga's ambitions-dasu!
다음 이야기! 에도토피아 대위기이오
Next story! Edotopia in Big Crisis
질풍노도의 초공전이오!
It's the stormy Chokuden-dasu!
다음 이야기
에도토피아
대위기이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Edotopia
in Big Crisis
Look forwards for it!